Guide to the Franklin M. Fisher Papers, 1958-2012 RL.11059
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Consulting Work, 1964-2010; 1
  - Expert Witness Files, 1972-2009; 1
    - St. Louis Convention and Visitors Commission vs. National Football League (NFL), et al., 1997; 7 folders (Box CW9)
      Declaratino of F. Fisher, Trial Transcripts, Deposition of F. Fisher, Defendant's Motion to Preclude Plaintiff's Damage Expert, Andrew Zimbalist, From Offering Expert Testimony, and Request for a Rule 104 Hearing
    - Superior Beverage Co., Inc., On Behalf of Itself and All Others Similarly Situated vs. Owens-Illinois, Inc., et al., 1990-1991; 9 folders (Box CW10)
      Depositions of F. Fisher, Deposition of F. Fisher, Economic Report, Trial Transcripts, Appendix to Defendant's Surreply in Opposition to Motion for Class Certification (including Supplemental Affidavit by F. Fisher), Appendix to Defendant's Memorandum in Opposition to Motion for Class Certification (including Affidavit by F. Fisher)
    - Telex Corporation and Telex Computer Products, Inc. vs. International Business Machines Corporation (IBM), 1972-1973; 2 folders (Box CW10)
      Affidavit of F. Fisher, Transcript of Proceedings
    - Texas Instruments Incorporations vs. Cypress Semiconductor Corp., LSI Logic Corp, and VLSI Technology, Inc., 1995 (Box CW10)
      Affidavit of F. Fisher in Response to TI's Motion for Entry of Judgment After Verdict
    - Thomas S. Daras, et al. vs. Texaco Refining and Marketing, Inc., et al., 1992; 2 folders (Box CW10)
    - Thomas S. Daras, et al. vs. Texaco Refining and Marketing, Inc., et al., 1992 (Box CW11)
    - Transnor (Bermuda) Limited vs. BP North American Petroleum, Conoco Inc., Shell Oil Company, BP Oil International Ltd., Conoco (U.K.) Ltd., Shell U.K. Ltd., Shell International Trading Co., Royal Dutch Petroleum Company, The "Shell" Transport and Trading Company, P.L.C. and Exxon Corporation, 1989; 2 folders (Box CW11)
      Deposition of F. Fisher, Affidavit of F. Fisher, Reply Affidavit of F. Fisher
    - Ultronics, Inc. vs. Cox Cable of San Diego, Inc./Cox Cable of San Diego, Inc. vs. Ultronics, Inc., 1990-1992; 6 folders (Box CW11)
      Deposition of F. Fisher, Declaration of F. Fisher, MDU Contract Charts: Introduction to the Revised Edition, Transcripts of Trial
    - Ultronics case supplemental research and testimony, 1990-1992; 3 folders (Box CW16)
    - Under 21, et al. vs. The City of New York and Mayor Edward I. Koch/The Salvation Army vs. Edward I. Koch, Mayor of the City of New York, et al./Agudath Israel of America vs. The City of New York, et ano., 1984; 1 folders (Box CW11)
    - Universal City Studios, Inc., Paramount Pictures Corporation, Metro-Goldwyn-Mayer Studios, Inc., Tristan Pictures, Inc., Columbia Pictures Industries, Inc.,Time Warner Entertainment Co., L.P., Disney Enterprises, Inc., And Twentieth Century Fox Film Corporation vs. Shawn C. Reimeredes, Eric Corley A/K/A "Emmanuel Goldstein", Roman Kazan and 2600 Enterprises, Inc., 2000; 2 folders (Box CW11)
      Deposition of F. Fisher, Trial Transcript
    - United States of America vs. American Society of Composers, Authors and Publishers, 1999 (Box CW12)
      In the Matter of the Application of Turner Broadcasting Systems, Inc., et al. for the Determination of Reasonable License Fees, Deposition of F. Fisher
    - United States of America vs. International Business Machines Corporation (IBM), 1974-1981; 7 folders (Box CW12)
      Depositions of F. Fisher, Pretrial Brief for Defendant International Business Machines Corporation, Direct Testimony of F. Fisher, The Surrebuttal Testimony of Fisher
    - United States of America vs. International Business Machines Corporation (IBM), undated (Box CW12)
      Bound Version of Historical Narrative Statement of Fisher
    - United States of America vs. International Business Machines Corporation (IBM), 1980; 1982; 5 folders (Box CW12)
      Direct Narrative Testimony of F. Fisher, Analytic Narrative of F. Fisher, Surrebuttal Narrative of Fisher, Cross-Examnination Deposition I of F. Fisher
    - United States of America vs. International Business Machines Corporation (IBM), 1980-1982; undated (Box CW15, CW16)
      Hardback bound copies of Analytical Narrative of Fisher, Vol. 1 and 2; Historical Narrative Statement of Fisher, et al; Cross-Examnination Deposition 1 and 2 of F. Fisher; Direct Narrative Testimony of Fisher; Surrebuttal Narrative of Fisher
    - United States of America vs. International Business Machines Corporation (IBM), 1981 (Box CW12)
      Cross-Examnination Deposition II of F. Fisher
    - United States vs. Microsoft Corporation, 1998-1999; 3 folders (Box CW12)
      Deposition of F. Fisher, Direct Deposition of F. Fisher, Trial Transcript
    - United States vs. Microsoft Corporation, 1999; 2 folders (Box CW13)
    - United States vs. National Broadcasting Company, In. (CBS), 1977 (Box CW13)
    - United States vs. Visa U.S.A., Inc., Visa International Corp., and Mastercard International Incorporated, 2001 (Box CW13)
      Decision of Justice, Analysis of Decision
    - United States vs. Western United Company, Inc., And American Telephone and Telegram Company, 1991; 2 folders (Box CW13)
      Reply Affidavit of F. Fisher, Affidavit of F. Fisher
    - United States Department of Labor vs. Harris Trust and Savings Bank Chicago, Illinois, 1985 (Box CW13)
    - U.S. House Committee on International Relations: invitation to testify re: Jordan River Basin water, 2004 (Box A1)
    - Visa Check/Mastermoney Antitrust Litigation, 1999; 2002; 5 folders (Box CW13)
      Deposition of Visa U.S.A., Inc. by William Sheedy, Supplemental Expert Reports of F. Fisher (including backup material), Supplemental Expert Report of James L. Brown, Supplemental Expert Report by Kenneth J. Morrison, Supplemental Expert Report by Benjamin Klein, Deposition of Witness George Benston
    - Overview and Economic Analysis of the Recent Mastercard/Visa Case, 2004 (Box CW13)
      New York State Bar Association Annual Antitrust Section Meeting (with Fisher as panelist)
    - Washinton Public Power Supply System Securities Litigation, 1987-1988; 8 folders (Box CW14)
    - Western Corporation vs. North American Chemical Corporation, and Eastern Corporation, 1985 (Box CW14)
      Record Contents
    - Unidentified Legal Cases, 1972; 1990-1994; undated; 8 folders (Box CW14)
      Various (including Exhibits Cited During Trial, Testimonies and Affidavits of Fisher)
    - F100 Cost Projects, vol. 2 (unknown case), undated (Box CW16)
    - Various F. Fisher deposition corrections, undated (Box CW16)
  - Projects, 1980s-2010; 2
    The majority of this subseries relates to Fisher's work with the Harvard Middle East Water Project; these files have not been arranged. Other projects represented include the Peace Now project and a consulting project for Singapore and Malaysia's water resources.
    - The Middle East Water Project materials, 1992-1994; undated; 13 folders (Box CW17)
      Includes correspondence, notes, research, articles, drafts, and other materials from Fisher and other collaborators
    - The Middle East Water Project WAS 3.3 Interpretative report, 1998 (Box CW17)
    - The Middle East Water Project WAS 3.2 and AGSM 1.1, 1997 (Box CW17)
      Water Allocation System (WAS) and Agricultural Sub-Model (AGSM) versions
    - The Middle East Water Project AGSM Interpretative Report, 1998 (Box CW18)
    - The Middle East Water Project AGSM model in the Palestinian districts, 1998 (Box CW18)
    - Why the Harvard Project will benefit Palestinians, 1993 (Box A1)
    - The Middle East Water Project research articles and related subject files, 1993-2000; 8 folders (Box A1)
      Collected files and articles about Middle East water and conflict resolution, including published reports.
    - WAS proposal for Czech Development Agency, 2008 (Box CW18)
    - Final report to Czech Development Agency: "Support to Infrastructure in the Palestinian Autonomous Territories with Emphasis on Water Management in 2008" (Box A1)
    - WAS - Palestinian Domestic Exercises, with Czech Development Cooperation, 2008 (Box A1)
    - WAS 3.3 Model in Palestinian Districts, 1998 (Box A1)
    - The Middle East Water Project participants directory, approximately 1998-2000 (Box A1)
    - CALVIN Project report (California Water Supply Model), 2003 (Box CW18)
    - Peace Now Project: Correspondence, articles, notes, 1980s-1994; 3 folders (Box CW18)
    - Singapore-Malaysia Water Agreements consultancy, 2003-2004 (Box CW18)
    - EIA Red Sea Dead Sea call for proposals, correspondence, 2007 (Box A1)
    - Water Saudi Arabia, 2010 (Box A1)
    - Friends of the Earth - Middle East: Draft agreement on water cooperation between Israel and Palestinian National Authority, 2008 (Box A1)
  - Workshops, 1986-1987; 3
    This subseries largely documents Fisher's work with the Antitrust Section of the American Bar Association.
    - Antitrust Seminar: Litigating "Rule of Reason" cases, 1986 (Box CW18)
    - Antitrust Seminar: Litigating "Rule of Reason" cases - The Retrial, 1987 (Box CW18)
    - Antitrust Seminar course material, 1986-1987 (Box CW18)
    - American Bar Association Antitrust Section correspondence, etc., re: institutes, 1986-1987 (Box CW18)
  - Service, 1976-1996; 4
    Fisher's community service and professional engagement with organizations like the Econometric Society, pro-Israel foundations, and other groups is documented in this subseries. Additional and related materials may be found in the Correspondence series.
    - Econometric Society meetings, correspondence, 1976-1977 (Box CW18)
    - Hillel Foundations of Greater Boston, 1980-1981 (Box CW18)
    - National Bureau of Economic Research Board of Directors meetings, 1993 (Box CW18)
    - Tel Aviv University Board of Governors meetings, correspondence, 1981-1986; 2 folders (Box CW18)
    - MIT Economics Forum materials, including newsletters, 1984 (Box CW18)
    - New Israel Fund, 1992-1996 (Box CW18)
    - Association for Civil Rights in Israel: litigation docket, 1988-1990 (Box A1)
  - Reports, 1964-2007; 5
    This subseries overlaps slightly with the Writings series; these reports were authored or collected by Fisher and relate to his professional work as a consultant for politicians, the FTC, and as a legal expert witness.
    - FTC Hearing: The Fisher Report, 1964 (Box CW19)
      Appendix to Reply Comments of the NAB
    - A Survey Study of Reenlistment Incentives, 1964-1965; 7 folders (Box CW19)
      Including cost/effectiveness research and appendices.
    - Robert Kennedy Presidential Campaign reports, 1967-1968 (Box CW19)
      Including draft proposals for the Educational Opportunity Bank, American Oil Policy, Enlisted Men Pay, and others
    - FTC Bureau of Economics Staff Report: Benefit and Costs of the FTC's Line of Business Program volumes, 1982-1983; 3 folders (Box CW19)
    - FTC: Understanding Single-Firm Behavior draft, 2007 Mar. (Box CW19)
    - Untitled study for Kodak, undated; 2 folders (Box CW19)
    - Rate of Return Issues in Partial Deregulation, undated (Box CW19)
    - China Country Assistance Evaluation draft, 2002 (Box CW19)
- Engagements, 1978-2008
  The Engagements series contains event files and correspondence documenting Fisher's invitations and participation in various professional events, largely conferences and economics summits. A portion of this series is grouped in loose chronological order; other portions are filed chronologically by event.
  - Miscellaneous board meetings, conferences, and travels, 1980s-2000s; 2 folders (Box E1)
  - Sogesta-Urbino conference, "Economic Planning for Government and Industry", 1978 Jan. (Box E1)
  - The World Bank visit, 1984 Apr. (Box E1)
  - MIT Economics Forum, 1984 Dec. (Box E1)
  - Trip to China, 1984-1985 (Box E1)
  - Johns Hopkins, 1985 Jan. 23 (Box E1)
  - Brown University: Economic Theory/Application workshop, 1985 Feb. (Box E1)
  - CRA Antitrust conference, 1985 Apr. 12 (Box E1)
  - Federal Trade Commission seminar, 1984 May 17 (Box E1)
  - University of Karlsruhe, 1985 July (Box E1)
  - Queen's University, Kingston, 1985 July (Box E1)
  - Harvard University Kennedy School: Conference on Technology and Capital Formation, 1985 Nov. (Box E1)
  - Conference Board workshop, 1986 Mar. (Box E1)
  - CRA Antitrust workshop, 1986 Apr. 18 (Box E1)
  - MIT Sloan School of Management, 1986 May 2 (Box E1)
  - NBER meeting, 1986 May 8 (Box E1)
  - IMSS summer seminars and workshops, 1986 (Box E1)
  - American Bar Association Antitrust Section national institute, 1986 Oct. (Box E1)
  - Harvard University: Economic Cooperation in the Middle East, 1989 Sept. (Box E1)
  - Antitrust conference, Boston, 1989 Oct. 13 (Box E1)
  - Journal of Merger and Acquisition Analysis, New York City, 1989 Oct. 21 (Box E1)
  - NBER/NSF conference, 1989 Dec. (Box E1)
  - Micro-BPEA meeting, Brookings Institution, 1989 Dec. (Box E1)
  - Harvard University: Economic Cooperation in the Middle East, 1989 Dec. (Box E1)
  - ASSA meeting, Atlanta, 1989 Dec. (Box E1)
  - Seminar on Economic Cooperation, London, 1990 May (Box E1)
  - ABA Antitrust meeting, Washington, 1990 Mar. (Box E1)
  - Jerusalem Economic Seminar, in honor of Don Patinkin, 1990 May (Box E1)
  - 5th conference, Karlsruhe, 1990 Aug. (Box E1)
  - NBER workshop on higher education, 1990 Oct. (Box E1)
  - Market Manipulation conference, Washington, 1990 Nov. (Box E1)
  - Micro-BPEA meeting, Brookings Institution, 1990 Dec. (Box E1)
  - Economic Cooperation in the Middle East, 1991 Feb. (Box E1)
  - Conference in honor of Zvi Griliches, Jerusalem, 1991 May (Box E1)
  - NBER (cancelled), 1991 Dec. (Box E1)
  - ASSA meeting, New Orleans, 1992 Jan. (Box E1)
  - University of Cincinnati lecture, 1992 Nov. (Box E1)
  - AEA meetings, Anaheim, 1993 Jan. (Box E2)
  - University of Manheim, 1993 Jan. 22-23 (Box E2)
  - CEMFI, Madrid, Spain, 1993 June (Box E2)
  - American Jewish Congress, 1993 Dec. 5 (Box E2)
  - Doing Business in the Middle East, 1994 Oct. 4 (Box E2)
  - Casablanca, 1994 Oct. 30-Nov. 1 (Box E2)
  - ABA Antitrust meeting, 1995 Apr. 6 (Box E2)
  - Rome conference: Pr. Paola Potestio, 1995 May 18-19 (Box E2)
  - Stockholm Water Symposium, 1995 Aug. 14-18 (Box E2)
  - Federal Judicial Center Workshop on Statistical Concepts, 1996 Jan. 10 (Box E2)
  - Baka Institute, Houston, 1996 Jun. 17-19 (Box E2)
  - Preservation of our World in the Wake of Change, Jerusalem, 1996 June 30 -July 4 (Box E2)
  - ABA "Basic Economics for Lawyers", 1996 Oct. 3-4 (Box E2)
  - Stockholm International Press Seminar: Water in the Year 2000, 1996 Aug. 5-8 (Box E2)
  - Zvi Griliches conference dinner, 1999 Mar. 5-6 (Box E2)
  - "New Directions in Antitrust," Center for Economic Policy Studies, Princeton, 1999 Mar. 12 (Box E2)
  - General engagements, 2000s (Box E2)
  - ABA meetings, 2000 Jan. (Box E2)
  - Second World Water Forum, The Hague, 2000 Mar. (Box E2)
  - ABA Spring meeting, Washington, 2000 Apr. 6 (Box E2)
  - Middle East Institute and the World Bank, 2001 May 15 (Box E2)
  - Honorary doctorate from The Hebrew University, Jerusalem, 2001 June 3 (Box E2)
  - Water in the Jordan Valley: Technical Solutions and Regional Cooperation, University of Oklahoma, 2001 Nov. 13-14 (Box E2)
  - Research in Income and Wealth, NBER, Cambridge, 2002 July (Box E2)
  - R and D, Education and Productivity, Paris conference, 2003 Aug. 25-27 (Box E2)
  - Water, Energy, and Environment Research Center, Beirut, 2004 Oct. (Box E2)
  - Sedona Conference, 2004 Nov. 4-5 (Box E2)
  - Expo Zaragova, Spain, 2008 July 28-31 (Box E2)
  - Americans for Peace Now annual meeting, 2007 (Box A1)
    seeking peace in Israel
  - World Economic Forum: Global Redesign Project presentation notes, 2009 (Box A1)
  - European Desalination Society: EuroMed conference, 2010 (Box A1)
  - New Israel Fund board meeting, 2010 (Box A1)